Guide to the Alice Key Papers
2016 The Regents of the University of Nevada. All rights reserved.
TEST Repository
Alice Key Papers
1936-1995
1966-1990 (bulk)
TEST Repository
Key, Alice
MS-00095
0.4 Linear Feet (1 box)
0.35 linear feet (1 box)
Collection consists of the papers of Alice Key, who came to Las Vegas in 1955 as Public Relations Director for the Moulin Rouge Hotel. Key had been a chorus girl in her early days in Los Angeles. Key was active in the Civil Rights movement in Las Vegas, and in a number of political and community service organizations such as the NAACP. Collection consists of clippings, photographs, correspondence, and videos regarding civil rights and entertainment, in particular, the preservation of the Moulin Rouge Hotel.
Acquisition Note
Materials were donated in 1995 by Alice Key; accession number 1995-047.
Access
This collection is open for research. Digital versions of this material are available through the UNLV Libraries website at: http://digital.library.unlv.edu/objects?CISOOP1=all&CISOFIELD1=CISOSEARCHALL&CISOROOT=all&CISOBOX1=MS+95-47&submit=Search+All
Biographical Sketch
Biographical Sketch
Alice Key was born in Kentucky around 1911. Her family moved to Southern California when she was still a small child. During her second year at UCLA, she was recruited as a chorus girl for the Cotton Club in Culver City, California, which began her long, successful dancing career.
In 1955, Key came to Las Vegas as Public Relations Director for the Moulin Rouge Hotel and, also, co-hosted the “Talk of the Town,” the first all-black television show in Las Vegas. From 1966 to 1969, she was editor of the Las Vegas Voice, the city’s first black newspaper. Always active in civil rights, Key was the director of the Nevada Commission for the Rights of Women from 1967 to 1969, coordinator for the Nevada Careers Program for the Equal Opportunity Board of Clark County from 1969 to 1972 and, from 1980 to 1983, she served as director of the Las Vegas branch of the NAACP. In 1983, Governor Bryan appointed her to the Labor Commission where she served for 10 years. In 1984, she helped organize the Barbara Jordan Democratic Women’s Caucus. She continued to be active in community affairs and at the time the collection was processed was working for the preservation and reopening of the Moulin Rouge Hotel in West Las Vegas.
For additional biographical information see: An interview with Alice Key: an oral history, conducted by Claytee D. White
Scope and Content
Scope and Content
The main topics in this brief collection are civil rights and the preservation of the Moulin Rouge Hotel. The collection includes certificates awards given to Alice Key, a little correspondence, invitations, programs, pamphlets and newspaper clippings. There is also some background information on Key's early life as a dancer. The donor noted that the photograph collection was assembled by someone else and is not in any rational order. Alice is writing some memoirs and will add them at a later date. Someone is also sending the newspaper columns she wrote which she will later add to the collection.
In 2003 an accretion was added consisting of 3 folders, which are described in the inventory below.
Arrangement of the Records
Arrangement of the Records
The collection is retained in a single series and divided into folders by topic and format.
Separated Materials
Eight photographs featuring Alice Key and other entertainment celebrities were removed to the UNLV Special Collections Photo Collection 0297.
Related Materials
Donald M. Clark Collection, MS-00158
Dancers; Public relations personnel -- Biography; Women newspaper editors -- Nevada -- Las Vegas -- Biography; Political activists -- Nevada -- Las Vegas -- Biography; African Americans -- Civil rights -- Nevada -- Las Vegas; African Americans -- Nevada -- Las Vegas; Las Vegas Voice; Talk of the town; Moulin Rouge Hotel and Casino -- History; Key, Alice
- Certificates and Awards, 1980-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1989-1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Invitations, 1965-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Las Vegas Review Journal, "Living" section, May, 19, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Las Vegas Review Journal, "Nevadan" section, September 17, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Las Vegas Review Journal "Nevadan" section, February 25, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Las Vegas Voice, July 21, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Newspaper clippings, 1936-1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Nevada Black History, Newspaper supplement, published 1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Photocopies and JPG images of photographs removed to Photo Collection 00297, circa 1940s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Programs, 1937-1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Pamphlets, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Video recording (VHS tape) Channel 8 KLAS-TV Black History Month: Alice Key, January 30, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Awards, certificates and proclamations, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence and speeches, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Newspaper and magazine clippings, 1980-2004 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Photographic prints, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Newspaper clippings, 1954, 1965, 1976, and 1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)